{
    "questions" : [
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [1~2] 다음을 듣고 알맞은 그림을 고르십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "26_1_img",
            "option_1"      : "① ",
            "option_2"      : "② ",
            "option_3"      : "③ ",
            "option_4"      : "④ ",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : Mr. Sumi, we're done with the meal, so do you want me to share some cakes with the guests?\nWoman : Yes, I'll cut it. Give me a plate there Man : Here you are.",
            "correctAnswer" : "② ",
            "score"         : "3",
            "isImg"         : "y"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [1~2] 다음을 듣고 알맞은 그림을 고르십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "26_2_img",
            "option_1"      : "① ",
            "option_2"      : "② ",
            "option_3"      : "③ ",
            "option_4"      : "④ ",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : Let's sit here for a while.\nMan : Yes. The art museum is quite wider than I thought. (I'm impressed) Oh, looking at it like this .The works also look new.\nWoman : Right? I think it's different from standing.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④ ",
            "score"         : "3",
            "isImg"         : "y"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [3~6]다음 대화를 잘 듣고 이어 질 수있는 말을 고르십시오",
            "question"      : "3. (3점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  내일 같이 병문안을 가 봅시다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  어제 사 준 약은 벌써 먹었어요.",
            "option_3"      : "③  힘들면 좀 일찍 들어가서 쉬세요.",
            "option_4"      : "④  감기에 잘 걸리지 않는 편이에요.",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : How's your body? I think you still have a bad face.\nWoman : I took the medicine in the morning, but it's getting worse.\nMan : If you're having a hard time, go in early and take a rest.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  힘들면 좀 일찍 들어가서 쉬세요.",
            "score"         : "3"
        },        
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [3~6]다음 대화를 잘 듣고 이어 질 수있는 말을 고르십시오",
            "question"      : "4. (3점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  주문하신 물건은 받으셨습니까?",
            "option_2"      : "②  다른 색깔로 바꿔 드리겠습니다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  더 큰 사이즈로 보내 드리겠습니다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  사이즈와 색깔을 말씀해 주시겠습니까?",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : Yes, this is Korean home shopping. Customer, how can I help you?\nMan : I'd like to order a hiking suit that's on air right now.\nWoman : Could you tell me the size and color?",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  사이즈와 색깔을 말씀해 주시겠습니까?",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [3~6]다음 대화를 잘 듣고 이어 질 수있는 말을 고르십시오",
            "question"      : "5. (3점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  하나씩 잘 가르쳐 봐요.",
            "option_2"      : "②  다른 회사로 옮기려고요.",
            "option_3"      : "③  입사 시험에 또 떨어졌어요.",
            "option_4"      : "④  드디어 첫 월급을 받았군요.",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : Director Kang, how are the new employees this time? Are you learning well?\nWoman : I'm working hard, but I'm still a little clumsy.\nMan : Teach me well one by one.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  하나씩 잘 가르쳐 봐요.",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [3~6]다음 대화를 잘 듣고 이어 질 수있는 말을 고르십시오",
            "question"      : "6. (3점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  역시 이곳 물건이 싸네요.",
            "option_2"      : "②  요즘엔 시장에 자주 와요.",
            "option_3"      : "③  앞으론 더 아껴 써야겠어요.",
            "option_4"      : "④  여기서 조금 더 사야겠어요.",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : I don't think I bought much, but I spent so much money.\nMan : I see. I think the price of goods has gone up a lot these days.\nWoman : I need to save more.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  앞으론 더 아껴 써야겠어요.",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [7~10] 다음은 무엇에 대한 내용인지 맞는 것을 고르십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "7. (3점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  노래를 듣는 사람",
            "option_2"      : "②  노래를 만든 이유",
            "option_3"      : "③  노래를 부르는 장소",
            "option_4"      : "④  노래를 잘하는 방법",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : This song is really fun, isn't it? I laugh every time I hear it.\nWoman : Right? This singer is the only love story that all the songs are similar these days.\nHe said it was so boring So I wanted to make a unique and fun song.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  노래를 만든 이유",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [7~10] 다음은 무엇에 대한 내용인지 맞는 것을 고르십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "8. (3점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  단어의 미와 사용",
            "option_2"      : "②  단어의 기능 과발음",
            "option_3"      : "③  단어를 외우는 비결",
            "option_4"      : "④  단어를 잘 찾는 요령",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman: It's time for a 'Korean walk'. Have you ever heard of the word 'becomeful'? This word means 'clean and small'. I mainly use it when I talk about the condition of the room or the outfit. For example, 'The room is so broken'. Or “Today’s clothes are really refreshing.” I can say",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  단어의 미와 사용",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [7~10] 다음은 무엇에 대한 내용인지 맞는 것을 고르십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "9. (3점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  음료수의 종류",
            "option_2"      : "②  음료수의 생산과정",
            "option_3"      : "③  음료수 성분의 차이",
            "option_4"      : "④  음료수의 판매율 변화",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : Which drinks have sold the most at the large mart in the past year? As a result of the survey, the juice sold the most, followed by soy milk and bottled water. Compared to 10 years ago, the share of sodas such as coke and cider has been reduced by half, but the sales of other drinks have more than doubled.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  음료수의 판매율 변화",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [7~10] 다음은 무엇에 대한 내용인지 맞는 것을 고르십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "10. (3점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  열차 점검 시기",
            "option_2"      : "②  열차 운행 시간",
            "option_3"      : "③  열차 탑승 절차",
            "option_4"      : "④  열차 사고 원인",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : There was an accident where the 391 train that left Seoul and went to Masan on the 8th stopped. The test showed that there was a problem with the thermostat. The official said that the machine seems to have froze due to a sudden cold wave, causing a problem, and he said that he would do more thorough preliminary inspection in the future.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  열차 사고 원인",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [11~13] 다음을 듣고 내용과 일치하는 것을 고르십시오. (각 4점)",
            "question"      : "11. (4점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  입병이 생기면 치아와 잇몸이 약해진다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  잇몸과 치아는 각각 닦는 방법이 다르다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  양치질을 강하게 하면 잇몸 건강에 좋지 않다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  이가 아플 때는 입 안을 더 깨끗이 해야 한다.",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : Did you go to the dentist?\nWoman : Yes. It is said that he got a wound on his gums because he brushed his teeth too hard. I thought it would be cleaner if I made it harder, but it wasn't. If you keep doing this, your teeth will get weak later, and you may have other diseases.\nMan : That's right. So I heard it's better to brush your teeth gently.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  양치질을 강하게 하면 잇몸 건강에 좋지 않다.",
            "score"         : "4"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [11~13] 다음을 듣고 내용과 일치하는 것을 고르십시오. (각 4점)",
            "question"      : "12. (4점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  공연은 오전과 오후에 한 번씩 진행된다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  공연 전에 동물들을 만져 보는 시간이 있다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  공연이 끝나면 바다 동물 사진을 나눠 준다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  공연에 가면 여러 바다 동물들을 볼 수 있다.",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : I'll let you know for a moment. The Seals venue has an exciting seal show every day from 2 p.m. to about 30 minutes. At the seal show, you can see not only seals but also amazing performances of sea animals such as penguins and dolphins. After the show, you can take pictures with the animals or touch them yourself. I hope you make good memories at Woori Land today.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  공연에 가면 여러 바다 동물들을 볼 수 있다.",
            "score"         : "4"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [11~13] 다음을 듣고 내용과 일치하는 것을 고르십시오. (각 4점)",
            "question"      : "13. (4점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  눈에서 열이 나면 눈을 자꾸 깜빡인다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  눈을 자꾸 비비면 눈물의 양이 줄어든다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  잠들기 전에 손과 발의 온도가 떨어진다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  혈액이 눈으로 이동하면 눈물이 많이 난다.",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : Children rub their eyes a lot when they are sleepy, right? What is the relationship between drowsiness and eyes? Our bodies drop their body temperature to use less energy while sleeping. So just before you fall asleep, a lot of blood temporarily moves to your hands, feet and eyes, sending heat out. At this time, when the eye starts to have a fever, the activity of the eyes becomes dull and the amount of tears decreases. Then you blink often and keep rubbing.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  눈에서 열이 나면 눈을 자꾸 깜빡인다.",
            "score"         : "4"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [14~17]다음 대화를 듣고 여자가 어떤 생각을 하고 있는지 맞는 것을 고르십시오.",
            "question"      : "14. (4점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  낙엽 청소하는 사람을 더 늘려야 한다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  낙엽은 쌓이기 전에 빨리 치워야 한다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  낙엽을 치우기 전에는 물을 뿌려야 한다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  낙엽을 치울 때 다치지 않게 해야 한다.",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : I think the road is a little messy because the fallen leaves have fallen.\nWoman : Right? In addition, the fallen leaves are wet and slippery, so you might fall while walking around. I don't know why I leave it as it is If it piles up more, the dust will get worse.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  낙엽은 쌓이기 전에 빨리 치워야 한다.",
            "score"         : "4"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [14~17]다음 대화를 듣고 여자가 어떤 생각을 하고 있는지 맞는 것을 고르십시오.",
            "question"      : "15. (4점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  서비스 센터의 상담원은 더 친절해야 한다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  서비스 센터에는 더 많은 상담원이 필요하다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  문제가 있으면 즉시 서비스 센터에 알려야 한다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  서비스 센터에는 점심시간을 피해 전화하는 게 낫다.",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : Ugh, I don't know what the hell is on the phone. I can't connect to the agent and the answering machine keeps repeating the same thing....... What service center is this?\nWoman : That's right. Are you really annoying But I tried it before and it didn't connect well during lunchtime. Try it after lunch time.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  서비스 센터에는 점심시간을 피해 전화하는 게 낫다.",
            "score"         : "4"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [14~17]다음 대화를 듣고 여자가 어떤 생각을 하고 있는지 맞는 것을 고르십시오.",
            "question"      : "16. (4점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  강의 내용을 다시 정리해 주면 좋겠다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  질문은 수업이 끝난 후에 하는 게 좋다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  강의 내용을 더 명확하게 설명해 주어야 한다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  수업 중에 서로의 생각을 나눌 수 있었으면 한다.",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : As expected, our professor's lecture is the best. You've clearly organized and explained the complicated content, so it's easy on your head.\nWoman : That's true. But I'm a pity that I don't have much time to discuss with the students. And I hope there will be more opportunities to ask the professor questions.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  수업 중에 서로의 생각을 나눌 수 있었으면 한다.",
            "score"         : "4"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [14~17]다음 대화를 듣고 여자가 어떤 생각을 하고 있는지 맞는 것을 고르십시오.",
            "question"      : "17. (4점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  가위의 손잡이를 고쳐야 한다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  가위질은 오른손 사용 연습에 효과적이다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  가게에서 왼손잡이용 물건도 팔았으면 좋겠다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  오른손뿐만 아니라 왼손도 사용하는 것이 좋다.",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : Oh, (married) I can't do it anymore.\nMan : Why? Don't you listen to scissors well?\nWoman: It's not that, I'm left-handed, but this is not for left-handed. Look at The direction of the handle is different, so it's hard to put your finger in.\nMan : I see. I need to buy one .\nWoman : I've already looked around the nearby stores, but there aren't any left-handed items. I wish I could put some things away.......",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  가게에서 왼손잡이용 물건도 팔았으면 좋겠다.",
            "score"         : "4"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [18~20] 다음 대화를 듣고 남자가 할 행동으로 알맞은 것을 고르십시오.",
            "question"      : "18. (3점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  다른 버스를 탄다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  지하철로 갈아탄다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  친구에게 전화를 한다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  휴대 전화를 찾으러 간다.",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : Oh, the car is really too crowded. I should have taken the subway instead of taking the bus. I know . Maybe there was an accident by any chance? Man at the appointment: I think I'm going to be late. What should I do?\nWoman : What time are you supposed to meet?\nMan : three o'clock. (After a while) I have to contact you because I'm going to be late. Uh ? Where is my phone? Didn't you bring.\nWoman : Don't you have it? Then try mine first.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  친구에게 전화를 한다.",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [18~20] 다음 대화를 듣고 남자가 할 행동으로 알맞은 것을 고르십시오.",
            "question"      : "19. (3점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  망가진 안경을 고치러 간다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  안경이 맞지 않아 다시 맞춘다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  시력을 확인하는 검사를 받는다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  시력을 보호하는 방법을 알아본다.",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : Well, these glasses. I set it here, but I don't think it fits well.\nWoman : Is that so? Can you give me a minute What's your name?\nMan: Kang In-ho. I did it last Tuesday If you use this from the day before yesterday, you'll feel dizzy and your head hurts.\nWoman : Is that so? Even if you look too good, you can have such a problem. I need to have an eye exam again.\nMan: So, do I have to put my glasses on again?\nWoman : Yes, in that case we'll do it again for free. I'm sorry",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  시력을 확인하는 검사를 받는다.",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [18~20] 다음 대화를 듣고 남자가 할 행동으로 알맞은 것을 고르십시오.",
            "question"      : "20. (3점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  공사 현장을 방문한다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  기술자를 현장에 보낸다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  공사장의 문제를 보고한다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  현장 직원을 본사로 불러온다.",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : Manager Kim, did you hear that there was a problem with the construction site?\nMan : Yes, I know. I heard that there was a strange sound from the machine and suddenly stopped. So I stopped working for a while and sent a technician to the site.\nWoman : Oh, I see. But just in case, Manager Kim, go to the scene as well. Please report it as soon as you know the cause. Please take a closer look at whether there are any safety issues.\nMan: Yes, I got it.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  공사 현장을 방문한다.",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            
          
            "sections"      : "※ [21~22] 다음 내용을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "21. 들은 내용으로 맞는 것을 고르십시오. ",
            "option_1"      : "①  이곳은 낮에는 문을 열지 않는다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  이곳에서는 대량으로만 물건을 팔고 있다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  이곳에서는 일반 쇼핑객이 물건을 살 수 없다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  이곳에서는 판매가 안 된 새 디자인도 볼 수 있다.",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : This is a clothing shopping mall in Seoul. It's so lively that I can't believe it's late at night. I'll have an interview with one of you here for a while. You look very busy, what are you doing now?\nMan: I'm preparing for business. A lot of shoppers usually come during the day, but at night, the owners of the clothing store come to buy things. Most of them buy dozens of clothes, so you have to take out a lot of things. And you want new designs that haven't been sold to the general public, so you have to display them separately.This is the busiest time of the day.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  이곳에서는 판매가 안 된 새 디자인도 볼 수 있다.",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [21~22] 다음 내용을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "22. 남자는 누구인지 고르십시오.",
            "option_1"      : "①  의상 디자이너",
            "option_2"      : "②  의류 상가 상인",
            "option_3"      : "③  의류 상가 쇼핑객",
            "option_4"      : "④  의류 상가 관리인",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : This is a clothing shopping mall in Seoul. It's so lively that I can't believe it's late at night. I'll have an interview with one of you here for a while. You look very busy, what are you doing now?\nMan: I'm preparing for business. A lot of shoppers usually come during the day, but at night, the owners of the clothing store come to buy things. Most of them buy dozens of clothes, so you have to take out a lot of things. And you want new designs that haven't been sold to the general public, so you have to display them separately.This is the busiest time of the day.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  의류 상가 상인",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [23~24] 다음 내용을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "23. 남자는 무엇을 하고 있는지 고르십시오.",
            "option_1"      : "①  ‘주차 시스템’의 기능을 소개하고 있다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  ‘주차 시스템’의 미래를 전망하고 있다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  ‘주차 시스템’의 개발 과정을 설명하고 있다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  ‘주차 시스템’의 설치 방법을 알려 주고 있다.",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : You've been wandering around once or twice because you didn't know the location of your car in the parking lot of the department store where a lot of cars are parked, right? Now I can get out of that concern. This is because more and more department stores are introducing a new 'parking system' for customer convenience. The system automatically remembers the parking location by the camera recognizing the vehicle number when customers park in the parking lot. After shopping, customers can see the fastest way to the parking lot by simply entering their vehicle number into the machine.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  ‘주차 시스템’의 기능을 소개하고 있다.",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [23~24] 다음 내용을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "24. 백화점들이 이 ‘주차 시스템’을 도입하는 이유를 고르십시오.",
            "option_1"      : "①  주차 관리를 잘하기 위해서",
            "option_2"      : "②  고객의 불편을 줄이기 위해서",
            "option_3"      : "③  주차 사고를 방지하기 위해서",
            "option_4"      : "④  고객의 차량을 보호하기 위해",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : You've been wandering around once or twice because you didn't know the location of your car in the parking lot of the department store where a lot of cars are parked, right? Now I can get out of that concern. This is because more and more department stores are introducing a new 'parking system' for customer convenience. The system automatically remembers the parking location by the camera recognizing the vehicle number when customers park in the parking lot. After shopping, customers can see the fastest way to the parking lot by simply entering their vehicle number into the machine.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  고객의 불편을 줄이기 위해서",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [25~26] 다음 내용을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오.",
            "question"      : "25. 여자의 생각으로 맞는 것을 고르십시오. (4점)",
            "option_1"      : "①  짧은 시간에 할 수 있는 일부터 먼저 한다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  일할 때는 한 가지 일에만 집중하는 게 좋다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  일하는 시간을 줄이면 집중력을 높일 수 있다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  뇌를 건강하게 하려면 다양한 일을 해야 한다.",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : Now, let's look at the next screen. This person writes documents and searches the Internet while talking on the phone. There must be people like this among you. You must have thought it was efficient to do a lot of work in a short time. However, unlike what I thought, it is said that the efficiency of work decreases. According to an experiment conducted by a research institute, the human brain does not do various things at once, but takes turns. Therefore, even if you get a lot of information at the same time, you will only process one by one. This leads to a lot of information getting tangled back and forth, slowing down the work processing speed and longer working hours.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  짧은 시간에 할 수 있는 일부터 먼저 한다.",
            "score"         : "4"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [25~26] 다음 내용을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오.",
            "question"      : "26. 여자가 제시한 주장의 근거로 알맞은 것을 고르십시오. (3점)",
            "option_1"      : "①  전문 기관의 연구",
            "option_2"      : "②  해외의 유사 사례",
            "option_3"      : "③  전문 서적의 내용",
            "option_4"      : "④  다른 사람의 경험",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : Now, let's look at the next screen. This person writes documents and searches the Internet while talking on the phone. There must be people like this among you. You must have thought it was efficient to do a lot of work in a short time. However, unlike what I thought, it is said that the efficiency of work decreases. According to an experiment conducted by a research institute, the human brain does not do various things at once, but takes turns. Therefore, even if you get a lot of information at the same time, you will only process one by one. This leads to a lot of information getting tangled back and forth, slowing down the work processing speed and longer working hours.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  전문 기관의 연구",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [27~28] 다음 내용을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "27. 여자의 생각으로 맞는 것을 고르십시오.",
            "option_1"      : "①  사람들과 빨리 친해지려면 이름을 불러야 한다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  직장에서는 직함을 사용해야 존경을 표시할 수 있다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  직함보다 이름을 부르면 의사소통이 잘 이루어진다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  직장에서는 서로의 할 일을 분명하게 구분해야 한다.",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : Some companies put 'nim' after the name or make a nickname instead of a title like an assistant manager or manager. It is said that if you call each other with this kind of name, the atmosphere will be free and good ideas come to mind. People communicate more actively when they are equal to each other.\nMan : I don't know I think everyone thinks differently. I saw a survey of office workers in a newspaper, and there were quite a lot of negative opinions. Actually, so is my opinion. There is no title, so the responsibility is not clear, so the work is not going well. In reality, few people call their names. And most of all, I don't think calling the name of the superior doesn't match the emotions of Koreans.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  직함보다 이름을 부르면 의사소통이 잘 이루어진다.",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [27~28] 다음 내용을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "28. 남자의 생각이나 태도로 맞는 것을 고르십시오.",
            "option_1"      : "①  차분하게 상황을 분석한다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  조심스럽게 반대 의견을 밝힌다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  솔직하게 자신의 잘못을 인정한다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  강력하게 문제에 대한 책임을 묻는다.",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : Some companies put 'nim' after the name or make a nickname instead of a title like an assistant manager or manager. It is said that if you call each other with this kind of name, the atmosphere will be free and good ideas come to mind. People communicate more actively when they are equal to each other.\nMan : I don't know I think everyone thinks differently. I saw a survey of office workers in a newspaper, and there were quite a lot of negative opinions. Actually, so is my opinion. There is no title, so the responsibility is not clear, so the work is not going well. In reality, few people call their names. And most of all, I don't think calling the name of the superior doesn't match the emotions of Koreans.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  조심스럽게 반대 의견을 밝힌다.",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [29~30] 다음 내용을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오.",
            "question"      : "29. 이 뉴스의 제목으로 가장 알맞은 것을 고르십시오. (4점)",
            "option_1"      : "①  농업용수 부족, 생각보다 심각해",
            "option_2"      : "②  물 부족 해결, 농업용수 줄여야 가능",
            "option_3"      : "③  물 부족 문제, 농업용수 문제로 이어져",
            "option_4"      : "④  농업용수 사용, 농작물 생산량 위해 늘려야",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : The use of agricultural water is becoming a problem in relation to the water shortage. This news, reporter Kim Min-soo, will deliver it to you.\nMan : The amount of water needed to produce one potato is similar to the amount of water a person can drink for two years. As such, the amount of water used in agriculture is beyond our imagination. So experts argue that we need to reduce agricultural water by more than 30% to solve the problem of water shortages. To this end, we have proposed water-saving crop cultivation techniques and automation of water management. In particular, he pointed out that 80% of agricultural water is used for rice paddy farming, and argued that technology that provides water efficiently should be developed as soon as possible, away from the current method of watering more than necessary.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  물 부족 해결, 농업용수 줄여야 가능",
            "score"         : "4"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [29~30] 다음 내용을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오.",
            "question"      : "30. 들은 내용으로 맞는 것을 고르십시오. (3점)",
            "option_1"      : "①  농업용수의 대부분이 논농사에 사용된다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  전체 물 사용이 늘면서 농업용수의 사용도 늘었다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  잘못된 농업용수 관리로 물 사용량이 30%나 증가했다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  현재의 재배 기술은 농업용수를 최대한 줄일 수 있도록 해 준다.",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : The use of agricultural water is becoming a problem in relation to the water shortage. This news, reporter Kim Min-soo, will deliver it to you.\nMan : The amount of water needed to produce one potato is similar to the amount of water a person can drink for two years. As such, the amount of water used in agriculture is beyond our imagination. So experts argue that we need to reduce agricultural water by more than 30% to solve the problem of water shortages. To this end, we have proposed water-saving crop cultivation techniques and automation of water management. In particular, he pointed out that 80% of agricultural water is used for rice paddy farming, and argued that technology that provides water efficiently should be developed as soon as possible, away from the current method of watering more than necessary.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  농업용수의 대부분이 논농사에 사용된다.",
            "score"         : "3"
        }
    ]
}
